[
    {
        "question": "The LORD is a jealous and avenging God; the LORD is avenging and wrathful; the LORD takes vengeance on his adversaries and keeps wrath for his enemies. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:2",
        "rank": "2,385"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD is good, a stronghold in the day of trouble; he knows those who take refuge in him. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:7",
        "rank": "3,157"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD is slow to anger and great in power, and the LORD will by no means clear the guilty. His way is in whirlwind and storm, and the clouds are the dust of his feet. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:3",
        "rank": "3,218"
    },
    {
        "question": "He rebukes the sea and makes it dry; he dries up all the rivers; Bashan and Carmel wither; the bloom of Lebanon withers. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:4",
        "rank": "3,433"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mountains quake before him; the hills melt; the earth heaves before him, the world and all who dwell in it. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:5",
        "rank": "3,626"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who can stand before his indignation? Who can endure the heat of his anger? His wrath is poured out like fire, and the rocks are broken into pieces by him. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:6",
        "rank": "3,826"
    },
    {
        "question": "But with an overflowing flood he will make a complete end of the adversaries,(1) and will pursue his enemies into darkness. Footnotes (1) 1:8 Hebrew *of her place* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:8",
        "rank": "4,069"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you plot against the LORD? He will make a complete end; trouble will not rise up a second time. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:9",
        "rank": "4,184"
    },
    {
        "question": "For they are like entangled thorns, like drunkards as they drink; they are consumed like stubble fully dried. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:10",
        "rank": "4,273"
    },
    {
        "question": "From you came one who plotted evil against the LORD, a worthless counselor. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:11",
        "rank": "4,310"
    },
    {
        "question": "(1) Behold, upon the mountains, the feet of him who brings good news, who publishes peace! Keep your feasts, O Judah; fulfill your vows, for never again shall the worthless pass through you; he is utterly cut off. Footnotes (1) 1:15 Ch 2:1 in Hebrew (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:15",
        "rank": "4,426"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD, \u201cThough they are at full strength and many, they will be cut down and pass away. Though I have afflicted you, I will afflict you no more. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:12",
        "rank": "4,592"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD has given commandment about you: \u201cNo more shall your name be perpetuated; from the house of your gods I will cut off the carved image and the metal image. I will make your grave, for you are vile.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:14",
        "rank": "4,612"
    },
    {
        "question": "And now I will break his yoke from off you and will burst your bonds apart.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:13",
        "rank": "4,715"
    },
    {
        "question": "And all for the countless whorings of the prostitute, graceful and of deadly charms, who betrays nations with her whorings, and peoples with her charms. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:4",
        "rank": "4,851"
    },
    {
        "question": "The shield of his mighty men is red; his soldiers are clothed in scarlet. The chariots come with flashing metal on the day he musters them; the cypress spears are brandished. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:3",
        "rank": "5,130"
    },
    {
        "question": "Behold, I am against you, declares the LORD of hosts, and will lift up your skirts over your face; and I will make nations look at your nakedness and kingdoms at your shame. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:5",
        "rank": "6,292"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will throw filth at you and treat you with contempt and make you a spectacle. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:6",
        "rank": "7,424"
    },
    {
        "question": "And all who look at you will shrink from you and say, \u201cWasted is Nineveh; who will grieve for her?\u201d Where shall I seek comforters for you? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:7",
        "rank": "7,737"
    },
    {
        "question": "The chariots race madly through the streets; they rush to and fro through the squares; they gleam like torches; they dart like lightning. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:4",
        "rank": "7,989"
    },
    {
        "question": "Are you better than Thebes(1) that sat by the Nile, with water around her, her rampart a sea, and water her wall? Footnotes (1) 3:8 Hebrew *No-amon* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:8",
        "rank": "8,179"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cush was her strength; Egypt too, and that without limit; Put and the Libyans were her(1) helpers. Footnotes (1) 3:9 Hebrew *your* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:9",
        "rank": "8,601"
    },
    {
        "question": "The river gates are opened; the palace melts away; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:6",
        "rank": "8,971"
    },
    {
        "question": "Woe to the bloody city, all full of lies and plunder\u2014 no end to the prey! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:1",
        "rank": "9,208"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nineveh is like a pool whose waters run away.(1) \u201cHalt! Halt!\u201d they cry, but none turns back. Footnotes (1) 2:8 Compare Septuagint; the meaning of the Hebrew is uncertain (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:8",
        "rank": "9,380"
    },
    {
        "question": "He remembers his officers; they stumble as they go, they hasten to the wall; the siege tower(1) is set up. Footnotes (1) 2:5 Or *the mantelet* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:5",
        "rank": "9,462"
    },
    {
        "question": "Yet she became an exile; she went into captivity; her infants were dashed in pieces at the head of every street; for her honored men lots were cast, and all her great men were bound in chains. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:10",
        "rank": "9,860"
    },
    {
        "question": "The scatterer has come up against you. Man the ramparts; watch the road; dress for battle;(1) collect all your strength. Footnotes (1) 2:1 Hebrew *gird your loins* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:1",
        "rank": "9,861"
    },
    {
        "question": "Desolate! Desolation and ruin! Hearts melt and knees tremble; anguish is in all loins; all faces grow pale! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:10",
        "rank": "10,205"
    },
    {
        "question": "You also will be drunken; you will go into hiding; you will seek a refuge from the enemy. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:11",
        "rank": "10,577"
    },
    {
        "question": "its mistress(1) is stripped;(2) she is carried off, her slave girls lamenting, moaning like doves and beating their breasts. Footnotes (1) 2:7 The meaning of the Hebrew word rendered *its mistress* is uncertain (2) 2:7 Or *exiled* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:7",
        "rank": "10,639"
    },
    {
        "question": "Plunder the silver, plunder the gold! There is no end of the treasure or of the wealth of all precious things. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:9",
        "rank": "10,779"
    },
    {
        "question": "There is no easing your hurt; your wound is grievous. All who hear the news about you clap their hands over you. For upon whom has not come your unceasing evil? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:19",
        "rank": "10,943"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lion tore enough for his cubs and strangled prey for his lionesses; he filled his caves with prey and his dens with torn flesh. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:12",
        "rank": "10,944"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the lions\u2019 den, the feeding place of the young lions, where the lion and lioness went, where his cubs were, with none to disturb? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:11",
        "rank": "11,083"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the LORD is restoring the majesty of Jacob as the majesty of Israel, for plunderers have plundered them and ruined their branches. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:2",
        "rank": "11,204"
    },
    {
        "question": "There the fire will consume you; the sword will cut you down \u2013  they will devour you like a swarm of locusts. Multiply like grasshoppers, multiply like locusts!",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:15",
        "rank": "11,428"
    },
    {
        "question": "Look at your troops \u2013  they are all weaklings. The gates of your land are wide open to your enemies; fire has consumed the bars of your gates.",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:13",
        "rank": "11,429"
    },
    {
        "question": "All your fortresses are like fig trees with their first ripe fruit; when they are shaken, the figs fall into the mouth of the eater.",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:12",
        "rank": "11,500"
    },
    {
        "question": "Horsemen charging, flashing sword and glittering spear, hosts of slain, heaps of corpses, dead bodies without end\u2014 they stumble over the bodies! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:3",
        "rank": "11,721"
    },
    {
        "question": "You increased your merchants more than the stars of the heavens. The locust spreads its wings and flies away. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:16",
        "rank": "11,793"
    },
    {
        "question": "Behold, I am against you, declares the LORD of hosts, and I will burn your(1) chariots in smoke, and the sword shall devour your young lions. I will cut off your prey from the earth, and the voice of your messengers shall no longer be heard. Footnotes (1) 2:13 Hebrew *her* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 2:13",
        "rank": "12,034"
    },
    {
        "question": "Your shepherds are asleep, O king of Assyria; your nobles slumber. Your people are scattered on the mountains with none to gather them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:18",
        "rank": "12,113"
    },
    {
        "question": "Your princes are like grasshoppers, your scribes(1) like clouds of locusts settling on the fences in a day of cold\u2014 when the sun rises, they fly away; no one knows where they are. Footnotes (1) 3:17 Or *marshals* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:17",
        "rank": "12,291"
    },
    {
        "question": "Draw water for the siege; strengthen your forts; go into the clay; tread the mortar; take hold of the brick mold! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:14",
        "rank": "12,382"
    },
    {
        "question": "The crack of the whip, and rumble of the wheel, galloping horse and bounding chariot! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 3:2",
        "rank": "12,461"
    },
    {
        "question": "An oracle concerning Nineveh. The book of the vision of Nahum of Elkosh. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Nahum 1:1",
        "rank": "15,731"
    }
]